准备好了吗？
You ready?
没想到我会这么紧张
Didn't think l'd be this nervous.
现在不做就永远不用做了
Now or never.
好了，老大，走吧
All right, papi, let's do this.
他在那里
He's over there.
你一定就是麦可
You must be Michael.
你的朋友费南多告诉我  你今天用得上我
Your friend Fernando tells me  you could use my services today.
没错
very much so.
我想那位就是你的另一半吧？
And l assume that's the other half  of your team?
你看起来好美
You look beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想你想要简单一点
lt's my understanding you'd like  to keep this simple.
我们总是把事情搞得很复杂
We've never actually managed  to keep anything simple.
可以试看看
You can try.
那我们开始好吗？
Well, let's begin then, shall we?
各位亲朋好友
Family and friends...
今天我们聚在这里一起祝贺
...we gather here  to celebrate the union...
麦可史柯菲和莎拉丹奎迪永结同心
...between Michael Scofield  and Sara Tancredi.
没错，老大
Oh, yeah, papi.
她有波多黎各血统，你看看她
This one has Puerto Rican blood  in her, l think. Look at her.
抱歉打扰你们的宴会
Sorry to break up the party.
- 怎么回事？  - 我们有逮捕令
-What is going on?  -We have an arrest warrant.
- 什么？  - 去问华府的保罗凯勒曼探员
-What?  -Talk to Agent Paul Kellerman in D.C.
我们几个礼拜前就已经  跟联邦调查局解决好了这件事
We settled this with the Feds.  We settled this weeks ago.
- 退后  - 我们已经被开释了
-Sir, back up.  -We were exonerated.
-Sir, back up.  -We were exonerated!
我们不是来找你，而是找她
We're not here for you.  We're here for her.
她什么也没做，她毫无关系
She didn't do anything.  She wasn't involved.
别闹事
Don't make this escalate.
莎拉丹奎迪，你因谋杀  克利丝汀娜汉普顿被捕
Sara Tancredi, you're under arrest  for the murder of Christina Hampton.
什么？她没有杀人
What? She didn't kill anyone.
真有趣，监视录影划面  可不是这么说
Funny. Surveillance-camera footage  says different.
麦可
Michael.
- 这边走  - 麦可
-Right this way.  -Michael.
- 请上第二台车  - 麦可
-Second car, please.  -Michael.
- 发生什么事？  - 别靠过来
-What's going on?  -Back up, please.
片名：越狱风云
他们不许我见她
They're not gonna let me see her.
如果你什么也不能做  凯勒曼为什么要你来？
Why did Kellerman send you  if you can't do anything?
他们想拆散你们两个
They're trying to break both of you.
她有被探访的权利
Look, she has a constitutional right  to visitation.
我会拟订裁定送给法官签署
l'll draw up an order  and get it before a judge.
你可以说是自卫吗？
Can you argue self-defense?
怎么说？
How?
现在没办法帮她
Anything that might help her  is out of frame.
监视划面显示莎拉走上前  朝受害者开枪
Security camera only shows Sara  stepping up and firing at the victim.
- 开枪啊，麦可  - 把枪放下
-Pull the trigger, Michael.  -Drop the gun.
开不了枪
Misfire.
- 她为公司工作  - 那是对你来说
-She worked for the Company.  -To you.
对陪审团来说她是技术顾问  克利丝汀娜汉普顿
To a jury,  she's Christina Hampton, consultant.
因为她太会隐藏真实身份  我们没办法证实
Because she was so good at hiding her  true identity, we can't prove otherwise.
你们全都无罪开释  让执法单位面子挂不住
Look, you were all exonerated.  lt did not sit well with law enforcement.
如果能让莎拉代罪  他们就会这么做
lf they can make Sara pay, they will.
她会被判几年？
How much time is she looking at?
二十五年或无期徒刑
Twenty-five to life.
（迈阿密戴德监狱，女子监狱）
（女舍，第三级）
Ladies, Level 3.
你睡这
You, over here.
You, here.
- 你睡这  - 没错
-You, here.  -That's right.
这张是你的
This one's yours.
我不应该被送到这里吧？
Aren't l supposed to be  in a different facility?
就是这里
l don't think so.
我还没被定罪，应该去看守所  这里是监狱
l haven't been convicted. l'm supposed  to be in a jail. This is prison.
那里太挤了，预算又被砍
Overcrowding and budget cuts, fish.
这边就是看守所
This is the jail.
那边是监狱
That's the prison.
放下就好
Just leave it there.
代码九十九号
Code 99.
怎么啦？
What's up, homey?
要帮忙吗？
You need some help?
需要的东西都有了吗？  你何不去帮她铺床
You got everything you need over there?  Why don't you go help make her bed.
茉莉警官请到康乐室
Sergeant Malloy to rec room.  Sergeant Malloy to rec room.
别让她们吓你
Don't let them spook you.
- 她们就喜欢威吓人  - 她们很有一手
-They just like to intimidate.  -They're good at it.
听着，监狱和看守所  混在一起真的很烂
Look, this jail-prison hybrid thing  is B.S.
来吧
Come on.
另一间几乎是空的
The other one's practically empty.
你就安心的在那等开庭吧
You can ride it out  till your court date there.
哪一间？
Which one?
谢谢
Thank you.
这里，这应该比较舒适
Here. This should be  a little bit more comfortable for you.
好
Okay.
怎么了？
What's going on?
刚开始
You know, at first...
我认不出你的名字
...l couldn't place your name.
丹奎迪
Tancredi.
听起来好耳熟
lt sounded so familiar.
赫克来了认出你是谁
Then Hucks here, figured it out.
我从报上记起你
l remembered your pretty face  from the papers.
你哪都别想去，新来的
You're not going anywhere, fish.
这会发生的
This is gonna happen.
福克斯河州立监狱有半打的守卫  没了工作和退休金
Half a dozen guards  lost their jobs and pensions at Fox River.
另外一半被判缓刑，因为你决定
Another dozen were put on probation  after you decided...
帮助你的男友  和他那七个罪犯兄弟潜逃
...to leave a door open for your boyfriend  and his seven convict pals.
我们不会让这样的事再发生
And we ain't gonna let anything like that  happen again.
不，过来，小亲亲
No. Come here, honey.
别担心，我们不会打到小孩
Don't worry,  we won't hit the baby basket.
- 没错  - 你看她
-Yeah.  -Look at her.
就是这样
That's right.
看来欢迎礼车刚压过你的脸
lt look like that welcome wagon  ran over your face.
看起来很像，对吧？
lt looks that way, huh?
我只是来帮助你适应
l just came by  to help you get adjusted.
如果你需要帮忙  这些警卫我都认识
lf you need something,  l know all these guards.
大部分的人都欠我
Most of them owe me.
很感谢，但我可以照顾自己
l appreciate that,  but l can take care of myself.
是我不对
My bad.
我也不知道为什么  我会觉得你照顾不了自己
l don't know what made me think  you couldn't take care of yourself.
好吧，需要什么就告诉我
All right, well, you need something,  you just ask for me.
大家都叫我老爹
Everybody calls me Daddy.
（迈阿密戴德监狱，男子监狱）
快递
Special delivery.
我们只需要拿点现金  来这里花花
You know, all we need is a little cash  to spread around the place.
我告诉过你，政府冻结我的资产
l told you,  the government's frozen my assets.
你是说你没办法拿到钱？
You telling me  you can't get your hands on any cash?
这是你该做的
That's the least you could do...
因为你不久前还想杀我呢
...considering you was gonna kill me  not too long ago.
再见，泰迪
Goodbye, Theodore.
你以前没被关过
You ain't ever been  incarcerated before...
我也没被关在这里过
...and l ain't ever been  incarcerated here before.
这样说好了，这个残废的囚犯
Let's just say this handicapped con...
尝不到在福克斯河监狱的甜头
...ain't got the juice he had  back in Fox River.
你和我的生活都能过好一点
Your pathetic existence here  could be ameliorated as can my life...
（丹奎迪因谋杀被捕）
只要拿点钱来花花
...all with a little Roberto dinero.
我们的一个朋友被逮捕了
One of our friends has been apprehended  by the authorities.
看来我们有位新邻居
Looks like we've got a new neighbor.
我知道我永远不能活着出去
l'm never gonna get out  of this prison alive, l know that.
我要拉我的敌人当垫背
l wanna bring my enemy down  with me.
我要她死
l want her dead.
（十万元，死）
不管怎样这都需要钱  但你已经没钱了
Either way, it's gonna require capital.  Capital you no longer have.
你知道我的备用基金在哪
My rainy-day fund.  You know where it is.
强纳森，那是你要用来打官司的
Jonathan, l'd assume that  that would be used for your defense.
花再多钱都没用，乔
lt's good money after bad, Joe.
不管我雇用多少律师  都没办法让我离开这里
They're not gonna let me out of here  no matter how many shysters l hire.
把它拿给我们隔壁女监的朋友
Get that to our friend in sister cells  across the compound.
可以坐下吗？
Excuse me.
不智之举
Bad move.
上次碰到她的人  膝盖骨被打断了
Last time someone touched her,  they got a cracked kneecap.
你比我想的还勇敢
You're much braver  than l give you credit for.
- 不是这样，就是你太天真  - 我看起来想跟你说话？
-Either that or you're amazingly naive.  -Do l look like l wanna talk to you?
像你这样的处境应该要找人罩你
Just saying a women in your position  would opt for some protection.
- 加入监狱帮派？我不干  - 不是帮派
-Join a prison gang? l don't think so.  -lt's not a gang, you know.
是家庭
A family.
她们不是平白无故叫她老爹
They don't call her Daddy for nothing.
那是她老婆
That's her wife.
其他是她的小孩
And those are her kids.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
离我远一点
Stay the hell away from me.
- 我要去医务室  - 没有命令就不能去
-l need to go to the infirmary.  -Can't go without a release form.
我喉头紧缩，下巴越来越紧
l'm having muscle contractions  in my throat and my jaw's tightening up.
是食用番木鳖鹼，老鼠药
lt's strychnine ingestion,  it's rat poison.
是公家的干酪，习惯吧
That's government cheese,  get used to it.
如果我十五分钟内没到医院  我和我的孩子都会死
lf l don't get to the hospital the next 1 5  minutes, l will die and my baby will die.
拜托
Please.
你何不让她去看医生？
Bo, why don't you let her go  see the doc?
拜托
Please.
我是考勒，有犯人要到医务室
This is Cowler. We have an inmate  going to the infirmary.
我们即时做活性炭灌洗
We were able to administer  the charcoal lavage in time.
你和宝宝都会没事
You and your baby are gonna be okay.
番木鳖鹼不会自己跑到我的肉块里
The strychnine didn't get in my meat loaf  all by itself, right?
你需要跟典狱长说
Well, then you need to talk  to the warden about it.
要不要跟我说你的脸怎么了？
Then how about talking to me  about your face?
要不要跟我说是怎么弄的？
You wanna tell me  how that happened?
我打篮球时弄伤的
l caught an elbow playing basketball.
我们应该讨论你的情况
We should discuss your situation.
我想你应该知道  这不会是一般的怀孕
l'm sure you've ascertained, this isn't  gonna be a run-of-the-mill pregnancy.
- 我会在这里生吗？  - 不会
-Do l deliver in here?  -No.
生的那一天会让你坐上救护车
The day we induce,  we'll secure you in an ambulance.
带你到邻近的圣露西亚医院  我们会封锁一个房间
Take you to Saint Lucia down the road.  We'll cordon off a room.
你生产时会有三个持枪的狱警驻守
There'll be three armed guards  when you give birth.
我可以看宝宝吗？
Do l get to see my baby?
抱走之前你有三十分钟
You'll have 30 minutes  before we take it.
这个过程我已经看过好几次了
l've seen this process a dozen times.
母亲回来之后  大多都难以承受那种低落
After the mothers come back here,  the depression's almost unbearable.
我的建议是
My advice...
如果你把自己想成  代理孕母会好一点
...it's less messy, if you just think  of yourself as a surrogate.
是的？
Yeah?
麦可，我是布鲁菲力普
Michael, it's Blue Phillips.
听着，你太太刚才发生意外
Listen,  your wife had an incident earlier today.
有人想要毒死她
Someone tried to poison her.
- 你在说什么？  - 麦可，你注意听
-What are you talking about?  -Michael, l need you to focus.
你知道可能是谁？
Do you have any idea  who might've done--?
麦可？
Michael?
麦可
Michael.
好的，让他进来
All right, let him in.
如果我有一张名单  上面写着谁可能会来看我
lf l had a list of all the people  who might come to visit me...
你的名字可能会在
...your name would be at the bottom,  somewhere below...
在耶稣和史酷比之后
...Jesus Christ and Scooby-Doo.
今天有人想毒死莎拉
Someone tried to poison Sara today.
还好没事
Mercy.
只有你才会坏到
Only you would be depraved enough...
认为杀害一个无辜的母亲  和她肚子里的孩子
...to think that killing an innocent  woman and her unborn child...
能让你在死刑之前  获得一点宁静
...would bring you some kind of peace,  before your execution.
莎拉怀孕了？
Sara is with child?
恭喜
Congratulations.
这像国庆日和圣诞节  合二为一的感觉
This is like the 4th of July  and Christmas rolled into one.
我以父亲对父亲的身份  求你放了她
l'm asking you, father to father,  to leave her alone.
如果你想杀就杀我  我愿意拿我的命换她
You can kill me if you wanna kill me.  l'll trade my life for hers.
不要动莎拉
But leave Sara alone.
麦可
Michael...
如果你被杀，痛苦只有一下子
...if you were killed,  your pain would last a moment.
如果莎拉被杀  你会痛苦一辈子
lf Sara were killed,  your pain would last the rest of your life.
这对那个动坏心眼的人来说  还蛮诱人的
Now, that's got to be appealing  to whoever put out this hit.
但是别担心，麦可
But don't worry, Michael...
如果我有什么消息  一定会告诉你
...if l find out anything,  l'll be sure to let you know.
（典狱长办公室）
监狱生活很辛苦
Prison life can be tough.
我记得你少了两只指头  可以作见证
l remember you have two missing toes  that can attest to that fact.
你不了解，她在这里很危险
l don't think you understand.  She's not safe here!
拜托
Please.
拜托把她转到别的监狱
Please just approve the transfer  to another facility.
如果我答应她  每个人就都想转
lf l grant her,  everybody's gonna want one.
那隔离房呢？
What about segregated housing?
隔离区的建筑结构完整性  有什么是我该知道的？
ls there something l should know about  the structural integrity of the SHU?
- 好吧，我知道你在想什么  - 我知道你是谁
-Right. l could see where this is going.  -l know who you are.
我不会让你把我的监狱  变成福克斯河监狱
And l'm not gonna let you turn  my prison into Fox River.
我会尽全力让我妻子活下去
All l'm trying to do  is keep my wife alive.
你知道她怀孕了吗？
You do know she's pregnant?
我不在乎
l don't care.
给你
Here.
- 谢谢  - 我想把话说明白
-Thanks.  -ln case l haven't made myself clear...
莎拉丹奎迪不会受到  特殊的待遇
...Sara Tancredi is not getting  any preferential treatment.
你已经说得很明白了
No, you've made yourself  perfectly clear.
谢谢你能见我
Thank you for your time.
怎么样？
What happened?
将军想让莎拉死  典狱长会放手让它发生
The general wants Sara dead  and the warden's gonna let it happen.
我们有律师，他会把她弄出来的
We got a lawyer on the case.  He's gonna get her out.
来不及了
There's not enough time.
她待在那所监狱，有人会杀了她
She stays in that prison,  someone's gonna kill her.
我想我们没有选择
l guess we don't have a choice.
我们去救她出来
We're breaking her out.
（芝加哥，伊利诺州）
我在局里工作十六年
ln my 1 6 years in the bureau...
我为四十三位探员工作过
...l've worked cases  under 43 different agents.
亚历山大曼宏是最干练、勇敢
Alexander Mahone  is the smartest, bravest...
最正直的人  我很荣幸跟他共事过
...most honorable man l've ever had  the pleasure of serving with.
身为四十三人的其中一个  我觉得有点冒犯
Well, as one of those 43 agents,  l can't help but feel a bit offended...
因为我跟一个  有毒瘾的杀人犯一样正直
...because, obviously l am not as  honored as this drug-addicted murderer.
亚历已经戒毒四个月了
Alex has been clean and sober  for four months.
跟公司有关的罪刑已经一笔勾消
And he's been completely exonerated of  all crimes associated with the Company.
这不包括谋杀奥斯卡席尔斯
That doesn't include the shooting  and murder of one Oscar Shales...
然后把尸体埋在水盆下
...and burying his body  under the birdbath.
这是凭空猜测
That is just an allegation.
我们继续好吗？
Let's move on, shall we?
所有赞成亚历山大曼宏复职
All those in favor of reinstating  Alexander Mahone...
成为联邦调查局特别干员的请表示
...as special agent  in the Federal Bureau of lnvestigation.
赞成
Aye.
- 反对的？  - 好吧
-All those opposed--?  -All right, all right.
这个
Well....
谢谢你邀我来
Thank you for the invite.
我很高兴
lt's always a pleasure.
亚历，这个裁定可以再议
You know, Alex,  this ruling can be revisited...
如果你能证明
...if you were able  to sufficiently demonstrate...
你有多投入一生为民服务
...just how committed you are  to a life of service.
你可能已经知道  莎拉丹奎迪最近被捕
Now, as you may know,  Sara Tancredi was arrested recently...
现在关在迈阿密戴德州立监狱
...and is currently being housed  at the Miami-Dade State Penitentiary.
我们担心麦可史柯菲想把她弄出去
We have concerns that Michael Scofield  may have plans for her.
这就是你们要我来的原因
So this--  This is why you invite me in here.
如果史柯菲能够
Well, obviously,  if Scofield were to be able...
成功策划另一次越狱
...to pull off this plot  of another breakout...
局里的脸就丢大了
...the public embarrassment  would be immense to the bureau.
如果有人能提供可靠的线索
So having someone to get us  credible information...
对我们来说非常有用
...that would be worth something  to us.
维特力探员会驻守迈阿密  他是你的联络人
Agent Wheatley is set up in Miami.  He would be your contact.
你真厉害
You're something else.
现在我们都知道  你多想回到原来的职务
Now, we both know  how badly you want that badge back.
给我个理由让你复职
Give me a reason to give it to you.
把她救出来后你有什么计划？
What's your plan  after we break her out?
- 我们又要逃亡？  - 重要的事先做
-We on the run again?  -First thing's first.
- 我们去救她出来  - 老大
-Let's get her out of there.  -Hey, papi.
逮捕莎拉的那个探员  在外面监视我们
The Fed that arrested Sara?  He's outside staking us out.
如果你们担心又要趟入浑水
Look, if you're worried  about getting into trouble again...
就回去芝加哥  回到家人的身边
...go back to Chicago.  Go back to your family.
我会理解的
l'll understand.
你说笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
在我们经历这么多事后  难道我会不顾你跟莎拉？
After all we been through, l'm gonna  leave you here and Sara there?
闭嘴，不要再提了  那些是什么？
Shut up and don't bring it up again.  What's all that?
剪报
Newspaper clippings.
包含七个不同的逃狱计划
Covering seven different  escape attempts...
是过去六十年  发生在迈阿密戴德州立监狱的计划
...from Miami-Dade State Pen,  over the last 60 years.
一个成功的案例都没有
None of them--  None of them successful.
我们看了之后  就知道哪些方法不可行
So we read them all  and we learn what not to do.
监狱官员学了很多  他们重新评估改进
The prison officials learned a lot.  They re-evaluated, they retrofitted.
这座监狱根本没办法逃脱
The prison's practically escape-proof.
- 你还好吗？  - 我很好
-You all right?  -l'm fine.
好，如果我们进不去  那么下降的方式呢？
Okay, so if we can't go through,  what if we go down?
我们跳伞进去，降到监狱中
Like, down into the prison.  We parachute in.
- 好  - 没错
-Yeah.  -Yeah.
- 找到她，带她出来  - 你在说笑？
-Find her, get out.  -Are you kidding?
- 我是认真的  - 这根本是自杀
-l'm serious.  -That's suicide.
我们只能从简报知道这么多
Hey, hey. Newspaper clippings  are only gonna get us so far.
我们要知道更多监狱的讯息  我们去做点功课吧
We need some more information about  the prison. Let's do some recon work.
相机，皮尺，干冰，这要干嘛？
Camera, tape measure, dry ice.  What's this?
这是张购物清单
lt's a shopping list.
跟我来
You need to come with me, doc.
我跟医师有约做产检
l have doctor's appointment  for my pregnancy.
可以待会做
lt'll wait.
进去
ln there.
等一下
Hold it.
我不知道你想要什么  但我会奋战到底
l don't know what you want,  but l will go down fighting.
该死，我不会伤害你的
Damn, baby, l ain't gonna hurt you.
我连碰都不会碰你
l ain't even gonna touch you.
我负责汽车修理场
See, l run the motor-pool detail  in here.
我在想如果你想要点新鲜空气
l was thinking, if you wanna  get yourself a little fresh air...
而不必担心被困在后面
...and not have to worry  about getting stuck in the back...
就来跟我工作
...then you can come  and work with me.
你是出现在我婚礼的探员
You're the Fed from my wedding.
- 叫我维特力探员  - 可以用来叫你的词可多了
-Call me Agent Wheatley.  -l could call you a lot of things.
- 你去哪？  - 海洋世界
-Where you headed?  -Sea World.
- 迈阿密没有海洋世界  - 我的损失
-Sea World. There isn't one in Miami.  -My loss.
不，如果你做蠢事  害你妻子被杀才是损失
No. What'd be your loss is getting your  wife killed by doing something stupid.
- 你威胁莎拉？  - 不，不是
-Are you threatening Sara?  -No, no. Not at all.
如果你想撤销她的刑期
l'm saying if you were gonna try  and revoke her sentence...
子弹可不长眼，麦可  不是她受伤就是你
...bullets fly, Michael. lf she were  to get hurt, that'd be on you.
听到把她关入大牢的人  这么说还真好笑
Funny hearing that from the guy  who put her in prison.
不，不是我关她  是佛罗里达州政府
No, l didn't put her in prison.  The state of Florida did.
我的职责是确保她待在里面
lt's my job to make sure  that she stays there.
你的那些兄弟呢？
So where's all your little buddies?
好，干冰多丢一点
All right. Drop in more dry ice.
（禁止闲晃、停车、逗留）
围墙距离路边四尺
Fence line is 4 feet from the road.
距东边摄影机二十二尺
Thirty-two feet from the east camera.
快点，他们会看到我们的雷射
Hurry up. They're gonna see our laser.
我尽量快了，老大
Going as fast as l can, papi.
他跟着你？
He follow you?
没错，但他走了
Yeah, but he's gone now.
你们快弄完了？
You guys almost done?
- 快了  - 很好
-Almost.  -Great.
我们阁楼见
l'll meet you back at the loft.
（迈阿密戴德诊所）
你真是天生好手
Well, you just a natural.
我想你是个外科医师吧
l bet you was a hell of a surgeon.
发保险套给囚犯  不会让你成为外科医师
Handing out condoms to cons  don't make you no damn surgeon.
- 你有什么毛病？  - 你都没问过我
-What in the hell is the matter with you?  -You ain't even ask me--
一天，我是认真的
One day. For real.
你可以一天不说话吗？一天
Can we go one day  without your mouth? One.
就是今天
Let it be today.
抱歉，原谅我家老太婆，她
l'm sorry.  You gotta forgive my old lady. She--
你看起来挺优的
You just a little bit easy on the eyes.
她很爱吃醋
And she's just a jealous type,  you know, so....
其实比较像疯婆子
Crazy type is more like it.
什么？注意你说话的语气，爱格莎
What?  You wanna watch your tone, Agatha.
- 对不起  - 还是要我抽皮带？
-Sorry.  -Or you want me to take off my belt?
对不起
Sorry.
小孩嘛
Kids.
组成一个家庭不简单，很辛苦
lt's rough. lt's hard running a family.
但很重要的是
lt's important though that--
你有个家
That you have one.
我有家，我有丈夫
l have a family. l have a husband.
你有丈夫，他有在这里？
Oh, you got a husband? ls he here?
他们能让他跟你一起来？
They let them bring you in here  with you when you came?
不行
No.
我也有丈夫
Yeah, l had a husband too.
十八年的等待太长了
Eighteen years is a long time to wait.
如果你不想加入
So, you know, if this ain't for you...
那也没关系
...that's cool.
把那些脏油拿出去
Then you pick up that nasty oil  and take it out...
倒在储藏器里
...and put it in the repository.
好
Okay.
我们走吧，老兄
We gotta go, bro.
没关系，别哭了
lt's okay, just stop your crying.
- 把你的手拿开  - 我满意就会放手
-Get your hands off me.  -When l'm good and ready.
柏劳在围墙边做什么？
What's Burrows doing by the fence?
别让我再问一次，莎拉
Please don't make me  ask you again, Sara.
没有人会罩你，你要不要说实话？
Nobody here to help you but yourself.  Are you gonna answer me?
你想杀我
You tried to kill me.
排好队，回来
Line it up, cons. Back inside.
回去做你的工作
You, get back to your detail now.
过来这里
Right over here, baby.
我要你跟你的朋友谈一项交易
l want you to pass along  an offer to your boy.
他想找人在女监收拾丹奎迪
What he's paying his people to dust  that Tancredi chick in bitch pop...
我马子打折帮他收拾
...my woman'll do it for a cut rate.
你说的是打几折？
Just what kind of discount  are you proposing here?
告诉他，如果原本出十万
Tell him  if he's offering a hundred grand...
我马子三万就做
...my girl will take 30.
不，四万
No, 40.
四万
Forty.
很好
Perfect.
我会告诉他
l'll tell him.
五星上将
Hey, five star.
如果你没有现金
So you have no cash...
一点也没？
...whatsoever?
抱歉
l'm sorry.
音响太吵我听不见
l couldn't hear you over the sound  of that broken record.
知道了
Got it.
我不会再问
l won't ask again.
他就跟你看的一样笨
He was acting stupid as you look.
怎么有这荣幸让您大驾光临？
Oh, to what do we owe the honor?
我一直在想
l've been thinking.
别害羞，直管说出来
Well, no need to be shy.  Just spit it out.
- 我改变心意了  - 是
-Changed my mind.  -Yeah, well...
或许老爹改变心意了
...maybe Daddy changed her mind.
也许她不想收你了
Maybe she don't want you here  anymore.
她说的没错
Squirt's right.
我已经收回我的善意
l recently have rolled up  my welcome mat.
保重
Peace.
拜托
Please.
拜托什么？
Please what?
让我加入家庭
Please may l be a part of your family?
出去走走
Take a walk.
我很欢迎  坐下，我真的是
l would love that. l would--  Sit down. l really would.
但没这么简单
But see, it's not that easy...
说个我愿意就好
...as just saying ''l do.''
你要许下诺言
See, you're making a commitment...
对家忠心不二
...to a family.
你必须证明
lt's something you gotta prove.
没错，我们都做过
That's right. We all did it.
这是对家徽的承诺
lt's a commitment to the family coat.
你必须戴上这个家徽
lt's a coat you gotta wear.
- 亚历  - 是你
-Alex.  -Hey.
- 什么事？  - 苏克
-What's up?  -Hey, Sucre.
- 你好吗？  - 怎么了？
-How you doing, man?  -What's going on?
我们谈谈
We gotta talk.
好
All right.
他们在监视你
They're watching you.
- 我们知道，有一个探员在跟我们  - 不，不只一个
-We know. We got a Fed on us.  -No. Not just one.
是整个部门
The whole department.
听起来像是内线消息，亚历
Sounds a lot like inside information,  Alex.
你怎么做，跟他们谈条件？
What'd you do,  make a deal with the Feds?
如果我来监视你  他们就让我复职
They offered me my job back,  if l came down here to spy on you.
你说的探员是维特力
The Fed you're talking  about is Wheatley.
- 他主导计划  - 我们现在知道了
-He's running point.  -So now we know.
如果你真的要做
So if you're really gonna do this...
就要做好
...you gotta do it right.
如果你需要，我会帮你
And l'll help you if you need me.
还有什么消息？
What else did you get?
莎拉今天四点在修车厂工作
Sara was working motor pool today  at 4:00.
修车厂在这里
Motor pool is here.
在监狱的范围有两个摄影机监视
visible by two security cameras,  along the perimeter of the prison.
- 有其他的入口？  - 没有卸货区，没有员工入口
-What about secondary entrances?  -No loading dock, no personnel entrance.
- 围墙呢？  - 十五尺高，有刺网
-Fences?  -Fifteen feet high, covered in razor wire.
- 有通电？  - 没有，为什么问？
-Electrified?  -No, why?
如果莎拉能回到修车厂
lf Sara can get herself back  to motor pool...
我们就可以找方法进去
...we can find our way inside.
翻修以后围籬线加宽了
With all the retrofits,  the fence line was widened...
但监视摄影机还是没变
...but security cameras remain  exactly where they've always been.
- 没有想到做了改变  - 有盲点
-Never accounted for the difference.  -A blind spot.
没错
Yeah.
这里，如果莎拉可以回到那里  我们就可以破坏围籬
Right here. lf Sara can get back  to that spot, we can breach the fence.
风险很大，麦可
lt's risky, Michael.
只能这样做，我们要告诉莎拉  在哪里碰头
lt's all we've got. We have to tell  Sara where we're gonna meet her.
怎么做？我们不能探视  也不能打电话
How? We get no visitation,  no phone calls.
这没问题，拿给丹奎迪
lt's clean. Take it to Tancredi.
记得我教你关于花朵的时刻
Remember when I taught you  about flowers.
我盼望此刻在你身边
I wish I was with you now...
看你手中握着一朵花儿
...to see you holding one in your hand.
To see you holding one in your hand.
明天，下午，七点，废油槽
Tomorrow, p.m., 7. Oil dump.
- 看来你一直很忙  - 你有搜索令吗，维特力探员？
-Looks like you've been busy.  -You have a warrant, Agent Wheatley?
搜索令？我不用
A warrant? No, l don't need one.
我会说是你兄弟让我进来
My testimony will be  that your brother let me in, once inside...
一进来就刚好看到这些证据
...saw all this evidence,  right in plain sight.
哪个法官会信你的鬼话？
What judge is gonna take your word?
什么证据？  这些都是公共建筑的照片
What evidence? Those pictures  were taken from public property.
监狱的资金是纳税人的钱
That prison was paid for  by the taxpayers.
你的证据只有一个无罪的市民
So all you have evidence of  is an exonerated citizen...
站在马路上拍摄公共建筑的照片
...standing on a public road taking  pictures of a public building.
这应该不算是犯罪吧
Last l checked, it's not a crime.
如果我说你有企图呢？
What if l said l could get you  on attempt?
你有这些东西
Just for having all this stuff.
如果我说这是表现善意的礼物？
What if l told you that all of this  was a peace offering?
典狱长不让我见我妻子
The warden  won't let me see my wife.
如果我找到一些安全漏洞
So l figured if  l found a few lapses in security...
然后善意的告知  或许她会改变心意
...pointing them as a gesture of good  faith, she might change her mind.
是这样吗？
ls that so?
- 你有发现什么？  - 没有，密不透风
-You find anything yet?  -Nope. Looks airtight.
你确定？
You sure about that?
没有混蛋可以混进去的地方？
Nothing that some scumbag  can exploit?
密不透风
Airtight.
真是谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness for that.
如果想到什么  你们会跟我说吧
But you guys will let me know  if anything comes up.
第一个就告诉你
You'll be the first to know.
放你一马
l won't keep you.
在外面，我以说到做到闻名
On the outside l was known  for getting the job done...
不管发生什么事
...no matter what.
我的报酬很丰厚
l got paid well for it.
现在我身无分文
Now l'm broke.
但我还是需要些东西
But l still need things.
像是什么？
Like what?
- 帮忙  - 我不帮犯人的忙
-A favor.  -l don't do favors for cons.
真的？
Really?
浴室的墙壁可不是这么说
That's not what it says  on the bathroom wall.
据我了解
As l understand it...
会回报的人你都会帮
...you do favors  for those who reciprocate.
真的吗？
ls that true?
干嘛
Hey.
这根本不算什么，老大
This is bush league, boss.
我是不死老兵
l'm a vet around here!
你我
You-- l--
没有理由翻我的东西
Ain't no reason to toss me!
你
You-- Hey!
你认识我
You know me!
看这里
Lookie, lookie here.
那包海洛因不是我的，你很清楚
No. That brown ain't mine,  boss, you know this.
我不吸毒
l don't do no drugs.
是谁栽赃我？
Who put that in here?
你
You--
放手，我知道在哪里关禁闭
Get your hands off me.  l know where the hole is.
你看什么看
What you looking at?
我不吸毒
l don't do no drugs.
这件事有人要倒大霉了
Somebody's going down for this.
我也爱你
l love you too.
苏菲亚在中美洲做了安排
Sofia's making arrangements  in Central America.
一旦救出莎拉就上船消失
Once we break Sara out,  we're on a boat, and we're gone.
- 你好  - 我是布鲁
-Hey.  -lt's Blue.
拿到法院的裁决
Got the decision from the court.
他们命令典狱长  允许监视下的探视
They're ordering the warden  to allow supervised visitation.
- 你去哪？  - 他们让我见莎拉
-Where you going?  -They're letting me see Sara.
他们会监听，你要小心
They're gonna be listening.  You gotta be careful.
如果她看懂我的信  就会想办法告诉我
lf she understood my letter,  she'll find a way to tell me.
怎么说？眨眼睛打摩斯密码？
How?  She gonna blink Morse code?
受刑人注意  访客时间五分钟后结束
Attention all inmates. Visiting hours  will be over in five minutes.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 是谁下的手？  - 我没事
-Who did this to you?  -l'm okay.
- 宝宝没事  - 莎拉，对不起
-Baby's okay.  -Sara, l'm so sorry.
你在这里都是为了我
You're in here because of me.
对不起，这真的很辛苦
l'm sorry, it's just hard.
- 我好想你  - 不许碰
-I miss you so much.  -No touching.
我也想你
I miss you too.
我们要撑住好吗？
We just have to hang in there, okay?
我很努力，但罩我的人不在
l'm trying, but my protection's gone.
收到我的信了吗？
Did you get my letter?
收到了
l did.
我知道有时很难表达我的意思
l know sometimes it's hard for me  to express what l wanna say...
但我希望你了解真正的含意
...but l hope you understood  what l meant to tell you.
我了解
l did.
他越来越可爱
ls he getting cute?
你以前挺我
You were there for me.
我也会挺你
l will be there for you.
好的
Okay.
好了，够了
All right, that's it.
时间到
Time's up.
很快会再见
See you soon.
再见
Bye.
各位请注意
Attention all....
请立刻回到牢房
Please proceed immediately  to the unit.
麦可
Michael.
关于阁楼里的照片和图样  我想了很多
l was thinking a lot about the photos and  the mock-up you showed me at the loft.
所以做了几个测试
And l ran a few tests.
你看，我找到盲点了
Lo and behold, l found a blind spot.
就在沿着围籬过去的那边  是翻修工程的漏洞
Right along the fence line over here,  due to a retrofit.
你应该不知道吧？
You didn't know about this, did you?
不知道
No.
如果你知道  早就告诉我和典狱长了吧？
No, because you would've told me  or the warden about it if you did, right?
还好我提早发现
Well, it's a good thing l found this  when l did...
现在还没人逃出去
...before anyone tried to escape.
进来
Coming in.
如果我们跨越不了围墙  就要往地下或天空发展
Well, if we can't go through the fence,  then that leaves under or over.
她要怎么爬铁丝网而不被抓？
How's she gonna climb  that fence without being seen, huh?
我想没有电话线可以让她爬过去
l'm guessing there's no telephone  wire for her to climb across.
那她就得从地下出来
Then she's gotta go under.
好吧，我们去买铲子
All right, let's get some shovels.
你说降落伞怎样？
What's that you were saying  about parachutes?
降落伞？
Parachutes?
别闹了
Guys, come on.
- 你不可能跳伞？  - 有几个问题
-You can't be s-- Parachutes?  -A couple of thoughts on that.
我们没有飞机也没有驾驶
A, we don't have a plane.  B, we don't have a pilot.
- 你有跳过伞？  - 别担心
-Have you ever worn a parachute?  -Don't worry.
我有计划
l think l've got a plan.
我们需要老朋友帮忙
We're gonna need some help  from an old friend.
谁？
Who?
你要我帮忙？
You want a favor from me?
听我说
Just hear me out.
当然，你和麦可送我回监狱时
Of course. l mean, when you and  Michael sent me back to that prison...
的确有给我一片口香糖
...you did give me the piece  of chewing gum.
如果不能回报，我还算什么？
What kind of man would l be  if l didn't quid your pro quo.
你只需要引发火警铃
Look, all you gotta do  is set off the fire alarm in here.
明晚七点三十分
Tomorrow night, at 7:30.
就这样
That's it.
你要救她出去？
You're breaking her out.
克伦札要杀她
Krantz has put a hit on her.
这是我们唯一的机会
lt's our one shot...
能够救她
...of keeping her alive.
这里是插翅难飞，林克
Well, you're in a pickle covered in jam,  Lincoln.
事成之后会给你五千
We'll put 5 grand in your kit  once this whole thing jumps off.
麦可一生的爱只值五千？
The love of Michael's life,  that's only worth $5000?
我们只有这么多
That's the best we can do.
- 我要六位数  - 我们只有这么多
-l need six figures.  -That's all we got.
你真幸运，我刚好知道谁有
Well, lucky day for you,  l know somebody who does.
将军的手下
The general's man.
他要拿钱付莎拉的杀手
He's got the payout for Sara's hit.
明天晚上七点前汇给我
You wire that money to me  by 7 p.m. tomorrow...
- 我就帮你  - 他叫什么名字？
-...and we're in business.  -What's his name?
- 叫你的兄弟利用他  - 给我多点时间
-Get your brother to use that noggin.  -You gotta give more.
明天晚上七点，去拿钱吧
Tomorrow at 7 p.m. Go on, fetch.
你还真难相处
You're a tough girl to get alone.
我知道他要来救你  我要跟你走
l know he's breaking you out.  l'm coming with you.
别紧张
Relax.
克伦札要我杀你
Krantz sent me to kill you...
但他那样对我，我不再听他的话
...but after what he's put me through,  l'm done.
我中毒时，你在我旁边
You were next to me  when l was poisoned.
如果我要你死，你还能活那么久？
You think you would've lasted  this long if l wanted you dead?
我要你死，你还是活着
l want you dead. You're alive.
你如果知道谁要搞你  就很难活下去
lt's hard to stay alive when you know  who's coming after you.
这边有二百个女囚
There's 200 women in this prison.
你以为你逃得出去？
Could you even get out of gen pop?
我跟你去
l'm coming with you...
要不然谁都别想出去
...or nobody's going.
你该看看麦可的表情
You should've seen Michael's face...
当他看到我修围籬，架摄影机
...when he saw me fixing that fence,  installing that camera.
你做的很好
You did a great job.
工作完成了
Well, the job's over now.
如果麦可误信莎拉命在旦夕
lf Michael has this misguided belief  that Sara's life is in danger...
他还是会找法子救她
...he's gonna find a way back  into that prison.
除非找到证据将他抓起来  否则你的工作就没完
Your job won't be over until you give  us evidence to put him back behind bars.
最新的动静如何？
So, what's the latest?
还没具体的行动
There's nothing concrete.
我有消息就告诉你
But l'll let you know  when l get something.
好的
All right.
很好
Good man.
如果你看到这影片
Well, if you're watching this...
我很高兴，因为这代表你很安全
...l'm glad  because that means you're safe.
- 他要怎么做？  - 从飞机往外跳
-How does he think he's gonna do this?  -Jump out of the plane.
- 我知道他要跳，但他能着陆吗？  - 不可能不被抓
-l know he's gonna jump. Can he land?  -Not without getting caught.
他要怎么逃出牢房？  即使茶包
How's he gonna get out of the cellblock?  Even if T-Bag--
这是大疑问，疯了才会相信茶包
lt's a big ''if.'' Trusting T-Bag is crazy.
麦可，我们真的要重新计划
Michael,  we really have to rethink this.
我想过了，没别的方法
l have. And there's no other way.
我降落在这个外围区域
Okay, l'm gonna drop down  into this outer area here.
在别人抓到我之前  我会切断降落伞
l'll cut the parachute off  before anyone can reach me.
他们一定会抓到你
They're gonna be on your ass.
我躲在这栋建筑之后  等待时机我就会到这里
l can hide behind this building, wait for  a window. l'll make my way over here.
那是教堂，希望莎拉能在那等
That's the chapel where, hopefully,  Sara will be waiting.
为什么是教堂？
Why the chapel?
在暴动的时候  员工可以从行政大楼逃出去
During a riot, prison employees  escaped through the admin building.
他们受伤倒在那里  就在围墙外
They wound up here,  outside the fence.
行政大楼跟教堂相接
The administration building  is connected to the chapel...
也就是在那道围场中  有个秘密出口
...which means that somewhere in that  compound, there's a subterranean exit.
如果我们能穿越
lf we can get through it...
你可以在这里等我们
...you can meet us there.
- 莎拉要怎么到教堂去？  - 她会找到方法的
-How's Sara gonna get to the chapel?  -She'll have to find a way.
我们按照计划明天晚上七点执行
Look, we're doing this at 7 p.m. tonight,  just like we planned.
你去哪了？
Where've you been?
我错过什么？
What did l miss?
我要你去找飞机和驾驶  我要你们去解决茶包的事
l need you to find a plane and a pilot.  l need you two to take care of T-Bag.
找出是谁有这笔钱  他们藏在哪里
Find out exactly who has this money  and where they're keeping it.
- 我们要拿到钱  - 今晚七点以前
-And then we have to get it.  -By 7 p.m. tonight.
不然莎拉就死定了
Or Sara's gonna die in there.
- 大家准备好了？  - 是的
-ls everybody onboard?  -Yeah.
好
Okay.
告诉我你完成任务了
Tell me you completed  your assignment.
我拿到现金  但是送到可能会拖一下
Well, l've got the cash, but there may be  some delay with final delivery.
那女人没办法接近莎拉丹奎迪
The woman we hired is having trouble  getting near Sara Tancredi.
找别人去，谁都可以，把赏金拉高
Hire somebody else. Call it open season.  Put a bounty on her head.
我不管你怎么做  我要莎拉丹奎迪活不过今晚
l don't care how you do it. l want Sara  Tancredi dead by the end of the day.
放封，一小时
Open cell. One hour.
我们要玩牌，你要玩吗？
Yo, we about to play cards.  Do you want in?
不要，谢谢
l'm okay. Thanks.
你应该要玩
You should.
老爹走了，你需要有人罩你
With Daddy gone,  you gonna need your backup.
我们都需要
Hell, we all do.
我怀孕有事
l've got a prenatal thing.
- 没关系  - 谢了
-lt's cool.  -Thanks.
有人出赏金要杀你  这样真不太聪明
Not too smart though for a girl  with a bounty on her head.
还是你没听到？
Or ain't you heard?
丹奎迪，你有访客
Tancredi, you have a visitor.
替我跟你老公问好
Say hello to your husband for me.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
听着
Look...
我知道这里发生的事你没办法控制
...l know you don't have any control  over what's happened here...
但事情不太顺利
...but things aren't working out.
好吧
Okay.
我一直在想办法去
l've been trying to find a way to do...
做这件事
...this...
但现在我们只有一个选择
...but from where we stand right now,  there's only one option.
你需要多点时间想想？
Do you need more time to think?
不，不是这样
No. No, it's not about that.
我已经想好了
I've made up my mind...
你没办法帮什么忙
...and there's really nothing  you can do about it...
只能今晚帮我们祈祷
...except pray for us tonight.
帮我们祈祷？
Pray for us?
我们可以祈祷相聚
You can pray for us to be together.
或许我也会这么做
Maybe l'll do the same.
如果我不知道是什么人  要怎么抢他？
How can l rob someone  if l have no clue who he is?
外面的簿子说  克伦札昨天有一个访客
The log book outside says  that Krantz had one visitor yesterday.
乔丹尼尔
A Joe Daniels.
以推论来说  丹尼尔就是你们要找的人
Well, using the power of deduction,  l'd say Daniels is your bagman.
你知道迈阿密有几个丹尼尔？  上千个，我要多点讯息
You know how many Daniels  live in Miami? Thousands. l need more.
那你最好快点
You better get cracking.
因为如果我七点前拿不到钱  你就别想我会触发火警铃
Because if l ain't got that money  by 7:00, you ain't got your fire...
我没触发火警铃  王子就找不到公主了
...you ain't got your fire alarm.  Pretty ain't got his Mrs. Pretty.
我的朋友  你没有立场要求
Listen, my friend,  you're in no position to make demands.
好吧
Okay.
我不是在乞求成交
l ain't talking about backing out  of the deal.
我会想办法弄点消息
l'll put my ear to the ground,  come up with some details.
很好
Good.
那就快去
Then go fetch.
找到驾驶了
We got a pilot.
我二十年前逮到这家伙  运毒越过波斯湾
lt's a guy l busted 20 years ago,  running drugs across the gulf.
改邪归正，现在做包机事业
Went legit,  runs a charter business now.
- 你应该跳过飞机吧？  - 有几次
-You must've jumped out of planes, huh?  -Yeah, several.
有些是运动，有些是需要  有很大的不同，麦可
Some for sport, some necessity.  lt's a big difference, Michael.
想降落在预计的目的地可没那么容易  尤其是晚上
lt's not easy hitting the X,  especially at night.
没问题，我可以自己来
Don't worry. l can go alone.
- 你在做什么？  - 一个测试
-What do you got?  -lt's a test.
监狱是在八十年代中期兴建
See, the prison was built  in the mid '80s.
行政大楼的门是用电子密码锁
That exit in the administration building is  protected by an electronic coded lock...
用安全卡改良而成
...modified by a security card.
这些锁没有电力保护
Those locks  don't have power protection...
也就是说你可以控制它
...which means  you can override them.
你不能去炸掉大楼的发电机
You can't go to the building's generator,  blow it out.
不行，一千二百伏特的  电流会触发警铃
No. Twelve-hundred-volt power surge  will just set off the other alarms.
而且也会杀了你
Not to mention maybe kill you.
所以我们要找其他方法
That's why we have  to find another way.
没错
Yeah.
- 曼宏，你查到什么？  - 目前没有
-Talk to me, Mahone. What do you got?  -Nothing yet.
我不用你跟我报新状况  我要证据、动机，不是没用的东西
l don't need updates on the hour,  l need evidence, intent. lt's not crap.
- 他犯罪时通知我  - 好
-Call me when he's committing a crime.  -Yeah.
我不会让他跑掉，就像你一样
l'm not gonna let him walk away  from me like he did you.
我要暗算他，他就完蛋了
He's going down  if I gotta shoot him in the back.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不知道
Well, l don't know.
好了，女士们
All right, ladies.
现在该我拿钱了，新来的
Time for me to get paid now, fish.
我们是朋友吗？
Are we friends now?
快离开
Get out of the way.
- 发生什么事？  - 我什么都没看到
-What happened here?  -l didn't see anything, sir.
- 走开  - 我也没看到
-Move.  -Me neither.
坏消息
Bad news.
爱格莎华伦死了
Agatha Warren is dead.
- 谁干的  - 没有人愿意招供
-Who did that?  -No one's talking.
但我听说是新来的
But l hear it's those fish.
丹奎迪和摩根
Tancredi and Morgan.
不
No!
他来了
Here he is.
如果你不喜欢，我们还可以找别人
lf you don't like this guy,  we can still find someone else.
很高兴见到你，史尼
Good to see you, Snee.
你想做什么，曼宏？
What you getting into here, Mahone?
- 一千五百尺跳伞不简单  - 你已经想反悔了？
-Jumping 1 500 feet ain't gonna be easy.  -You going back on your word already?
别忘了到底是谁帮谁
Let's not forget  who's doing who a favor.
帮忙？帮忙
A favor? A favor.
你老婆贩毒我有抓吗？  没有，我没抓
Did l bust your old lady for trafficking?  No, l did not.
有人问起，我就说我只负责载人
Anyone asks,  l was flying a tourist through the Keys.
他要跳下去不是我的错
And it's not my fault they jumped.
听起来不错
Sounds good to me.
如果你不喜欢这个人  我们再延一天，想新方法
lf you don't like this guy, take a day.  Come up with a new plan.
不，没时间了，亚历
No. There's no time, Alex.
不只是莎拉命在旦夕
lt's not just Sara's life at risk.
我了解
l understand that.
我知道，所以我想请你帮忙
l know you do. That's why l also know  l can ask for your help.
- 好，什么忙？  - 如果我有不测
-Yeah. What do you need?  -lf l don't make it...
确保莎拉和我哥可以活着逃出国
...make sure Sara and my brother  get out of the country alive.
我要知道他们没问题
l need to know they're gonna be okay.
我相信你会尽力完成这件事
And l'm gonna trust that you'll do  everything you can to make that happen.
拿着
Take this.
我相信你，亚历
l trust you, Alex.
要记得
Remember that.
（给莎拉和林克）
快递
Special delivery.
什么东西？
What is it?
我不太知道
l don't exactly know.
是从女监那边拿来的
lt came via messenger  from the lady's side.
“我在外面的人想知道  打电话给谁拿生日礼物”
''My man on the outside needs to know  who to call for the birthday present.''
是谁的生日？
Who's birthday is it?
确定它会回到原来的地方
See to it  it gets back to the same place.
没问题
Will do.
这是乔丹尼尔的电话是吗？
So this is Joe Daniels' number, right?
就这样，够多了吧  还是你想要身份证号码？
That's it. ls that enough information  or you need a social security number?
- 这样够了  - 记得
-That'll do.  -Remember...
钱要汇到我的帐户
...l want that money wired  to the account number specified.
没汇钱就没火警
No wire, no fire.
我不用担心，可以快乐的庆祝吧
Do me wrong, l'll have no qualms at all  about singing loud and clear.
你知道的，准备好吧
You know what, just be ready.
那是苏菲亚
That was Sofia.
他会在圣安卓港跟你见面
She'll meet you  in the San Andres Harbor...
- 然后你们就去哥斯大黎加  - 很棒
-...then you guys can fly to Costa Rica.  -Cool.
我知道丹尼尔的下落
l know where Daniels is.
抢到钱以后我就会把钱汇到银行
After we rob him, l'll take the money  to Quik Green and wire it to the bank.
- 在机场碰面  - 我们会试试看
-Meet us at the airstrip.  -We'll give it shot, yeah.
好了，就这样
Okay. This is it.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
谢了，老兄
Thanks, buddy.
所有的一切
For everything.
祝好运，老大
Good luck, papi.
另一边见
See you on the other side.
没人说话？  有人死了，大家都没看见？
Nobody's talking, huh? A girl's dead  and no one said anything, huh?
罗沙瑞，下一个是你
You're next, Rosario.
让路
Get out of my way.
床没问题
The bed, it's perfect.
（爱蜜莉）
我在木工店做的
l made it in the wood shop.
我要在生日时给我女儿  爱蜜莉生日礼物
l wanna give my daughter, Emily,  a birthday gift on her actual birthday.
所以我要出去
That's why l need to get out of here.
- 真是多愁善感  - 我没有
-How very sentimental.  -Oh, l'm not.
只有为她
lt's just for her.
你聪明就快招
lf you're smart, you'll start talking.
我们要去教堂
We need to get to the chapel.
- 我们？  - 现在出不去
-We?  -There's no way out of here right now.
我需要你
l'm gonna need you.
- 是的  - 丹尼尔先生
-Yeah.  -Mr. Daniels.
美国油漆公司来工作
American Paint Company here  for the job.
我就是丹尼尔，我没叫人油漆
Well, this is Mr. Daniels,  but l didn't order any painters.
今天星期三，我想你有
It's Wednesday. I believe you did.
别动，我会叫警察
Okay, hold it right there.  l'm calling the police.
出来
Get up.
到了
This is it.
我马上回来，我会买降落伞
l'll be right back.  l gotta get that parachute.
（出清跳伞用具）
麦可
Michael.
过来
Come here.
有别的方法
There's a better way.
吃饭
Mess.
吃饭，半小时
Mess. Half hour.
快点，快出来
Okay, let's go, girls. Get out.
快一点，没有整天的时间跟你耗
A little faster. We don't have all day.
我们走
Let's go.
- 有办法吗？  - 有
-Got any ideas?  -Yeah.
低着头跟我走，我会想出办法
Keep your head down and follow me.  l'll think of something.
排好队
Oh-nine, in the line.
你最好快点想，我们有同伴了
You better think of something fast  because we have company.
我希望你准备好打架  这次至死方休
l hope you're ready for a fight, princess.  This one's to the death.
你想能撂倒她？
Do you think you can overpower her?
可以
Yeah.
我想你该担心的不是她
l don't think it's her  you have to worry about.
准备好
Just be ready.
- 你好  - 是我
-Hello?  -lt's me.
我收到关于生日礼物的消息
l got the message  about the birthday present.
有人来领了吗？
Was the gift earned?
- 你在胡说什么？  - 生日礼物
-What the hell are you talking about?  -The birthday present.
生日礼物？两个人闯到我家
Birthday present?  Two guys showed up at my house.
他们把钱拿走，痛扁
They took the money  and they beat the crap out of--
你好，将军
Howdy, general.
我只想告诉你我最近有点钱
Oh, l just thought l'd let you know,  l came into some green.
我喜欢两条花生糖棒  和一本时代杂志
My personal preference is two  Zagnut bars and a copy of The Times.
我们早上见？
So l'll see you in the a.m.?
没用的杂种
You worthless son of a whore.
下地狱吧
Go to hell!
小心我没有先去
Careful l don't get there first...
要不然我也会变成那边的头
...lest l become king  of that prison too.
从起飞到监狱的时间很短
All right, from take off,  the prison's gonna come up real fast.
要准备什么，现在就弄好
So whatever you gotta do to get ready,  do it now.
没问题
You got it.
我们拿到钱了  苏克放下我就去汇钱了
We got the money. Sucre just dropped  me off on the way to wire it.
很好，茶包的事搞定
Good. That means T-Bag's set.
我看他还要多久才能起飞
l'm gonna see how long  it's gonna take him to get going.
- 当然，你会拖延吗？  - 没问题
-Sure that thing's gonna hold you up?  -Yeah, it'll be fine.
你怎么样？
What about you?
又不是第一次进监狱
lt's not my first time inside prison.
但希望是最后一次
But hopefully, it'll be my last.
想想看你可以告诉你儿子  多么精彩的故事
Think about all the amazing stories  you'll be able to tell your kid.
你会变成我们老爸  做不到的那一种爸爸
You're gonna be the type of father  our dad never was.
让人钦佩的那一种
Someone to look up to.
小心，麦可
Take care, Michael.
没有详细的计划，我就挂了  把复职的事忘了吧
Unless you've got details l'm hanging up.  You can forget getting your badge back.
他找了台飞机要跳伞到操场
He's got a plane,  gonna parachute into the yard.
- 什么？  - 我发誓
-What?  -l swear to God.
他会在七点的时候通过监狱上空
He's gonna be over prison airspace  at 7:00.
要求增派人手  我要二十个武装警卫到操场
Call in reinforcements.  l want 20 armed COs in the yard.
准备关掉外面的灯
Be ready to turn off exterior lights.
史柯菲看清一切就太迟了
Scofield won't see what's coming  until it's too late.
把莎拉丹奎迪带来
And bring me Sara Tancredi.
等等
Wait. Wait--
爱格莎发生的事不是这样的
What happened with Agatha,  it's not what happened.
我要跟你讲清楚好吗？
l need to make this right with you,  okay?
说啊
Go ahead.
我希望能在这看到你
l was hoping l'd see you here.
我还欠你一个大人情
You know l still owe you  one big juicy favor.
等下，蓝眼妹
Later, blue eyes.
我发誓她想杀我  我只想自卫而已
l swear to God, she wanted to kill me  and l was just defending myself.
- 记得这个？  - 记得
-Remember that?  -Yes, l do.
我妈给我的
My mama gave me that.
要我有一天把它给我的孩子
Told me l was gonna give it  to one of my kids one day.
我从未怀孕，但我组成一个家庭
Now, l never did get knocked up,  but l grew a family.
爱格莎是我养大的  她才不会杀人
And l practically raised Agatha  and she wasn't no killer.
我现在没什么好说
Now, l can't say that much for myself.
我还不知道要做什么
You don't even know  what l had in mind yet.
你说对了，爱格莎不会杀人
Okay, listen, you're right.  Agatha isn't a killer.
她太贪心，吃不下来还敢接
She was just a greedy little bitch  who bit off more than she could chew.
史奇朵
Skittlez.
没事
Okay. We cool.
We cool.
没事，我
We cool. We--
考勒，典狱长要你带丹奎迪  去她办公室
Cowler, Simms wants you  to bring Tancredi to her office.
好的
All right, okay.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
他们会经过这里，知道吗？
They'll be coming by  through here, okay?
陶德维特力探员  我现在要进去
Federal Agent Todd Wheatley.  l need to get inside right now.
- 紧急小组先  - 我是紧急小组的头
-Emergency Team takes priority.  -l'm leader of the Emergency Team.
- 让我进去  - 我有命令
-Let me inside.  -l have orders.
去跟你的上司说
Go talk to your supervisor. Come on.
艾文，让他们过
Yo, Evan, let the Suburban through.
飞机随时会到
That plane should be overhead  any minute.
各位，把灯关掉
Hey, fellas, kill the lights.
他一落地就开火
As soon as he hits the ground,  that's when l want you to start firing.
准备
Stand by.
我们在准备了
We're standing by.
别紧张，先别开火
Easy now. Hold your fire.
准备
Stand by.
开火
Now.
- 走吧，靠过去  - 靠过去
-Let's go. Move in, men.  -Move in, move in.
- 别开火  - 准备
-Hold your fire. Hold your fire.  -Okay, stand by.
靠过去
Moving in.
史柯菲呢？
Where the hell is Scofield?
- 紧急小组先  - 我是紧急小组的头
-The Emergency Team takes priority.  -l'm the leader of the team.
- 现在让我进去  - 我收到命令任何人都不许进出
-Now, let me inside, right now.  -l have strict orders no one gets inside.
我不管什么命令  跟你的上司说
l don't care what your orders are.  Go talk to your supervisor.
为什么丹奎迪还没来？
Why isn't Tancredi in front of me?
我们才刚平息纷争
We just got this situation  under control.
我们在找她
We're looking for her right now.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 你还好吗？  - 是摩根
-Are you all right?  -lt was Morgan.
去厨房看看，她们也许在厨房
Check the kitchen.  They might be in the kitchen.
我自己办不到
l'm not gonna make it on my own.
放下我或带我走，下决心吧
Either leave me or don't,  but make up your damn mind.
你办得到吗？
You gonna be able to make it?
可以
Yeah.
好，现在
Okay. lt's now.
天啊
Oh, God.
等等
Whoa, hold up.
没事
No, l think we're good.
（新教教堂）
别动
Don't move!
马上趴下
Skirt in the dirt, now!
- 拜托，我只是  - 趴下
-Please, l just--  -On the ground!
你一个人吗？
You here alone?
该死，我在问你，快回答
Damn it, when l ask you a question,  you answer.
还有别人在这吗？
ls there anyone else here?
有
Yes.
谁？
Who?
上帝
God.
再说一次
Excuse me?
他总是在这
He's always here.
我担心外面的女儿
l was worried about my little girl  on the outside.
所以来祷告
So l came to pray.
希望有人照顾她
See if someone will watch over her.
去看看
Go check it out.
牢房需要人手  我们要把这些野兽关起来
I want some asses in the cellblock. We  gotta get these animals locked down.
我们最好快回去
We better head over there.
希望你的女儿比你聪明
l hope that daughter of yours  is a lot smarter than you.
我也希望
So do l.
来了
Hey.
准备走了吗？
You ready to go?
没人可以进出  就算是总统要小便都不行
Nobody gets in or out of prison.  l don't care if it's the president...
叫他滚回去，找一组人马
...having to take a piss. Tell him  to turn the hell around. Get a team.
看看围籬有没有被破坏
l want that fence line  checked for points of compromise.
是的
Yes, sir.
麦可说他们会从这里出来
Michael said this is where  they're gonna come out.
你觉得苏克来得及吗？
You think Sucre  made the drop on time?
不知道
Don't know.
（营业中）
（快汇公司）
不
No, no, no.
（关门，请再来电）
请输入帐号
Please enter your account number.
三，四，八，井号
Three, four, eight, pound.
您的帐户余额为零元零分
Your account balance  is zero dollars and zero cents.
如果想听取下一个帐号
If you would like  to access another account--
九，二，四，八，井号
Nine, two, four, eight, pound.
您的帐户余额为零元零分
Your account balance  is zero dollars and zero--
你在干什么？  我们要封锁了
What the hell do you think  you're doing, fish? We in lockdown.
为什么？
What for?
女监出事了，不知道是什么事
Something's going on in bitch block,  l don't know.
发现会得到什么好处？
What's it worth to you to find out?
我们要穿过这里？
Are we gonna get through here?
另一边是行政大楼的逃生门  以防暴动
The other side is kind of an escape hatch  for the administrators, in case of a riot.
福克斯河监狱用的是同一套系统
This is the same system they have  in Fox River.
门只能由控制室开启
That door can only be open remotely  from the control room.
所以我们需要帮忙
That's why we had to ask for help.
茶包
T-Bag.
告诉他们你跟我说的
Tell them what you told me.
麦可史柯菲要劫狱
Michael Scofield's about  to stage a prison break.
我知道他要怎么做
And l know exactly  how he's gonna do it.
史柯菲到底要你做什么？
Exactly what did Scofield  ask you to do?
触发火警铃，其他的他会处理
Just light a fire in my cell  and the rest will just take care of itself.
触发火警铃会启动什么程序？
Fire alarm. When that goes off,  what's your protocol?
州政府规定疏散
State law, mandatory evac.
他不会救她出去  他会摆你们一道
He wasn't gonna break her out,  he was gonna get you to.
- 闭嘴  - 把他带出去
-Shut up.  -Get him out of here.
疏散也只能到操场
All right, the evacuation's only gonna  get him out of the yard.
不管他做什么都需要噪音和混乱
Whatever he's up to,  he needs noise and he needs chaos.
解除烟雾侦测系统和火警铃
Deactivate the smoke detection system,  the fire alarm.
你做的时候，不要声张
And while you're at it, kill the horn.
这里一有风吹草动
lf anybody so much as bends a blade  of grass in this place...
我都要听到
...l wanna be able to hear it.
我们在等什么？
What are we waiting for?
我们做了交易
We made a deal.
价钱谈妥，茶包就会触动警铃
For the right price,  T-Bag would set off the fire alarms.
我们在等这个
That's what we were waiting for.
- 麦可，有  - 没关系
-Michael, there's a--  -lt's okay.
跟茶包谈生意只有一件事可以确定
There's only one thing you can count on  when you're dealing with T-Bag...
他是个爪耙子
...he's a rat.
- 有事吗？  - 一个女囚跑到操场
-Anything?  -Just female inmate loose in the yard.
- 丹奎迪？  - 不，摩根
-Tancredi?  -No, Morgan.
叫做葛蕾琴
First name, Gretchen.
- 在教堂边  - 好
-Over by the chapel.  -All right.
好
All right.
好，我们走
Great. Now, let's go.
好，下去
Okay. Down there.
好
Okay.
这门后面应该是一百码的隧道
Beyond this door should be  a hundred yards of tunnel.
那一边是林克
On the other end of that is Linc  and after that...
之后会有一艘船航向白砂碧海
...there's a boat bound  for white sand and blue water.
强大的电流通过系统
A power surge to the system...
会控制读码器几秒
...will override the reader  for just a few seconds...
时间够你打开门，所以准备好
...just long enough for you  to open the hatch, so get ready.
三，二，一
Three, two, one.
再一次
One more time.
三，二，一
Three, two, one.
我就怕这会发生
l was afraid this might happen.
没关系
lt's okay.
没关系，我们往前走再想别的办法
lt's all right. We're gonna keep moving.  We're gonna find another way.
我知道该怎么做
l know what l have to do.
派人到教堂
l need units to the chapel, now.
五十三组收到
Unit 53, 1 0-4.
- 他们在哪？  - 我不知道
-Where are they?  -l don't know.
他们现在应该到了
They should've been here by now.
电池的电力不够
The battery wasn't generating  enough power.
我们要毁掉整栋大楼的电力
We have to blow the system  for the whole building.
好，你要怎么做？
Okay. What do you wanna try?
这是主要保险丝
This is the main fuse.
我一拉，就会变黑几秒
lf l yank that,  everything will go dark for a second.
我再把两条苐线接起来
lf l reconnect these two cables....
如果我把两条苐线接起来  会有很大的噪音
lf l reconnect these two cables,  there'll be a lot of noise.
每个灯泡都会破
And every bulb is gonna blow.
这时就马上开门出去
As soon as that happens,  open that hatch...
我要你快跑
...l want you to start running.
好，那你呢？
Okay. What about you?
麦可
Michael.
莎拉
Sara...
有人要留下来
...someone has to stay here.
有人要去开门
And someone has to open the hatch.
那就是你
And that someone's gonna be you.
我开着让你走
Okay. So l'll leave it open for you.
你不明白
You don't understand.
这是唯一的方法
This is the only way.
你跟我走，否则我不走
l'm not leaving  unless you're coming with me.
我是跟你走
l am coming with you.
我爱你
l love you.
我也好爱你
God, l love you too.
快走
Go.
快走，莎拉
Go, Sara.
快走
Go.
在楼下
Down the stairs.
麦可呢？
Where's Michael?
莎拉，麦可在哪？
Sara, where's--?
麦可在哪？
Where's Michael?
他在哪？
Where is he?
他不会回来了
He's not coming back.
他不会回来是什么意思？
What do you mean  he's not coming back?
是什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
他不会回来了
He's not coming back.
他会回来
He'll be here.
他走了，林克
He's gone, Linc.
林克，要走了
Linc, we gotta go.
要走了
We gotta go.
一下就会开放
Hey, it's gonna be open in a minute.
为什么要惩罚我？
Why am l being punished?
我警告你们
l'm the guy who blew the whistle!
你协助教唆逃亡，包威先生
You aided and abetted an escape,  Mr. Bagwell.
主管单位认为你是共犯
As far as the authorities are concerned,  you're an accomplice.
史柯菲
Scofield!
麦可说如果他有不测  要我把这个给你
Michael asked me to give you this  if he didn't make it out.
他说这能帮你了解他的作法
He said it would help you understand  why he did what he did.
他的验血报告
lt's his blood work.
（检验报告  麦可史柯菲）
（脑瘤）
这是将军的钱
This is the general's money.
我本来应该汇到哥斯大黎加给你
l was supposed to wire it down  to Costa Rica for you to pick up...
但我遇到一些困难
...but l ran into some trouble.
对不起
l'm sorry.
好好照顾孩子好吗？
You take care of that baby, okay?
你也是
You take care of yours.
给你的
lt's for you.
他什么都没跟我说
He never said anything to me.
他为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't he just tell me?
因为他知道你会阻止他
Because he knew  you'd try to stop him.
他知道你会不计一切保护家人
He knew you'd do anything  to protect your family.
但我没有
But l didn't.
这个
Well...
就快有了
...you will soon.
放轻松
Take it easy.
莎拉
Sara.
谢了
Thank you.
不客气
Yeah.
如果你看到这影片，我很高兴
Well, if you're watching this,  I'm glad...
因为这代表你很安全
...because it means you're safe.
这是我的衷心期望
And that's all I ever wanted.
我好希望能跟你在一起
I wish I could be there with you.
但可能你已经知道
But as you probably know now...
反正，我剩下的日子也不多了
...I wouldn't have had much time  anyway...
所以我做出了选择
...so I made my choice...
就绝不后悔
...and I don't regret it.
不久之后
Anyway, not too long from now...
就会有小史柯菲在这里跑来跑去
...there's gonna be another little Scofield  running around.
林克，我要你答应我  无论如何
And, Linc, I want you to promise me,  no matter what...
你都要陪在我孩子的身边
...they're gonna grow up  knowing their uncle is never far away.
莎拉
And, Sara...
我要你答应我看着林克
...I want you to promise me  that you're gonna keep an eye on Linc.
你可能已经发现他老是有麻烦
As you may have noticed,  he has a tendency to get in trouble.
你们知道吗，我们耗费生命
You know,  we spend so much of our lives...
却说不出我们最想说的话
...not saying  the things we wanna say...
我们应该说的话
...the things we should say.
我们隐藏真意  我们借由纸鶴传递讯息
We speak in code  and we send little messages, origami.
现在我只想简简单单的说
So now, plainly, simply...
我爱你们两个
...I wanna say that I love you both.
很爱很爱
Very much.
我要你们答应我
And I want you to promise me...
你们会告诉我的孩子
...that you're gonna tell my child--
你们会告诉我的孩子  每天都有人深爱着他们
That you're gonna tell my child  how much they're loved every day.
提醒他们自己有多幸运
And remind them  how lucky they are...
能够自由自在
...to be free...
因为我们就是这样
...because we are.
我们现在自由了
We're free now...
终于
...finally.
我们自由了
We're free.
[MANDARIN- R3]  [ENGLlSH]